#### **RESUME**

Name : **Mr. Komalkumar Turkar** 

Current Organisation : Sutra Services Pvt. Ltd. | sumHR.com

Current Designation : Technology Lead

Previous Organisation : Synage Software Pvt. Ltd. | DeskAway.com &

Brightpod.com

Experience : 10 Years

Email : komalturkar@gmail.com

Mobile No : +91-9167030456

Twitter : komalturkar

Linkedin : https://in.linkedin.com/pub/komalkumar-turkar/17/49/18

### **Technical Skills**

Web Technologies : JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ajax, jQuery, XML, JSON

Core Technologies : PHP 4 & 5

Databases : MySQL, MongoDB

Web Server : Apache, Nginx

Server Knowledge : Rackspace, Linode, Azure (Basic)

Operating Systems : Linux, Mac & Windows

PHP Framework : CodeIgniter & YII

Version Control Tool: Git and SVN

Integrations / API : Dropbox, Rackspace Cloud Files, Freshbooks, Google Apps,

Google

Chooser, Box, AWS, Intercom

Payment Gateway : 2Checkout, CCAvenue, PayPal, SaaSy (Fastspring), PayUMoney

CSS Framework : Bootstrap, Skeleton

Email API : Mailgun, Postmarkapp, SendGrid

#### Achievement

Worked with a SaaS startup from beginning based in Mumbai, India and helped it achieve successful name around the world. It's DeskAway.com. Currently managing a small team which includes development team, online support, billing & online marketing for sumHR.com

## Responsibility as a Technology Lead:

- > Managing Development Team. Make sure that branching process goes smooth and resolve any merge conflicts.
- ➤ Manage Testing Team. Ensure that features are bug free. Reviewing testing cases and scenarios.
- Make sure that development process is smooth, on time & meets deadline.
- > Responsible for Requirement gathering of any new feature. Create tasks, allocation and execution.
- ➤ Work towards product / feature areas which can be automated.
- > Manage support team and guide them to work towards providing best customer service.
- > Bringing new technologies and app which can save time of development team and product management.
- > Responsible for the server management.
- > Transparency of developer work to higher management.
- > Solely responsible for hiring UI developer, PHP developer, Software tester etc.
- > Involved in code review.
- > Responsible for daily scrum meeting with team in morning about their agenda & follow up in evening what they have done.

### **Responsibility as a Developer at the Same Time:**

- > Managing the Administrator part of the core product.
- ➤ Involved in coding and managing the billing system of the product including payment gateway.

- > Involved in any third party app integration with the product.
- > Responsible for assisting developers when need be.
- > Responsible for UI development of any new feature & existing feature.
- ➤ Involved in Unit testing of self written code.

# **Professional Experience Summary**

10 Years of work experience in LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, & PHP) on Product and Various Projects.

Strong analytical skills & good problem solving approach. Ability to work under pressure & deadlines.

Good understanding of Team dynamics, work independently & Team handling.

Worked on SaaS based online web 2.0 tool from scratch till it gets success.

Worked on Mobile & iPhone site of the project.

Plugged multiple payment gateway with the project like: 2Checkout, ccAvenue, PayPal, PayUMoney.

Work on integration with third party tool like: Freshbooks, Google Apps, Intercom.

Moved existing clients data to cloud using Rackspace cloud files.

Worked on various API's to integrate product with them.

### **Current Employment**

Organization : Sutra Service Pvt. Ltd.
Period : April-2014 - till date
Designation : Technology Lead

Role / Profile : Planning, Team handling, Customer Support, Unit Testing,

Testing, Coding, Database Architecture, etc.

Online Product : http://www.sumHR.com (Online Human Resource

Managment Software)

Period : April 20014 – currently working

Team size : 6 - 9 (3 dev, 2 software tester, 1 dot net engg, 2 customer support)

Technologies Used : Yii, MongoDB, PHP, MySQL, Ajax, Jquery, Node, etc.

Framework : YII Framework, Bootstrap,

Role : Technology Lead

Project in Brief : sumHR, is a web-based human resource management software that provides HR to companies to help manage Attendance, mange Leaves, manage Payroll, small inbuilt section for company activity, etc.. You can read more about sumHR here: <a href="https://www.sumhr.com">www.sumhr.com</a>

## **Previous Employment History**

Organization : Synage Software Pvt. Ltd. | DeskAway.com | Brightpod.com

Period : July 2005 – March 2014

Designation : Lead Developer (Chief Code Chef)

Role / Profile : Planning, Customer Support, Unit Testing, Coding, Database

Architecture etc.

Also involved in Social Media, Customer Support & Online Marketing, etc.

Online Product (1): http://www.DeskAway.com (Online project management

software)

Period : 2006 – 2011

Team size : 6-9

Technologies Used : PHP, XML, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ajax, Jquery.

Framework : Core PHP, (osCommerce - Basic Structure)
Role : Lead PHP Developer (Chief Code Chef)

Project in Brief : DeskAway, is a web-based project collaboration software

that provides teams a central location to easily organize, manage and track their projects & work. It is SaaS (Software As A Service) based tool. It has mobile as well as iphone web versions. You can subscribe for free as well as trial accounts and later on you can subscribe for paid version using online payment gateway. DeskAway is listed on Google's Marketplace. So, if you have Google Apps account then you can sign up form there also. DeskAway targets clients across the global. You can read more about DeskAway here: www.deskaway.com

Online Product (2): <a href="http://www.brightpod.com">http://www.brightpod.com</a> (Online collabration software for

digital marketing agencies)

Period : 20011 – 2014

Team size : 2-3

Technologies Used : PHP, XML, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ajax, Jquery.

Framework : CodeIgniter, Bootstrap
Role : Lead PHP Developer

Project in Brief : Brightpod.com is a web based collaboration tool for online marketing teams to help them get organised. This project is build with MVC framework called as CodeIgniter, UI framework called as Bootstrap.

# **Educational Qualification**

Bachelor's Degree B.Sc. (Computer Science) in Year 2004 from Nagpur University, Maharashtra, India.

### **Personal Details**

Present Address : Kandivali West, Mumbai

Date of Birth : December 31st 1982

Marital Status : Married. Having 1 kid.

Languages Known : Marathi, Hindi, and English.